<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Python Matters</title>
      <link>/blog/why-python-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/why-python-matters/</guid>
      <description>The debate regarding “R versus Python” is one that is largely based on statistics versus CS/ML. Each language has its own advantages however, we can conclude that both languages are very useful and can actually work together.
Here are example of differences between R and Rython: After becoming very familiar with R all semester, learning about Python was quite interesting. We can use library(reticulate) to conduct some python coding in RStudio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Inference, Prediction</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>I have decided to use the CrohnD dataset from the package robustbase. This dataset provides information regarding the number of adverse events caused by a drug used to treat patients sufferring from Crohns disease.This is dataset is composed of 117 observations on 9 variables: ID (patient identifcation number),nrAdvE (number of adverse events), BMI (Body MASS Index), height (in cm), country (a factor with levels 0 and 1),sex, age, weight (in kilograms) and finally treat (how CD was treated: a factor with levels 0, 1 and 2, meaning placebo, drug 1 and drug 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Data Wrangling and Exploratory Analysis</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: I will be using two different datasets from R-studio. The first dataset that I will be using is called bad_drivers. This dataset contains 51 observations and 8 variables. The 8 variables are num_drivers, perc_speeding (percent of drivers that were speeding), perc_alchol (percent of fatal collisons due to alcohol), perc_not_distracted (percent of drivers that were not distracted causing a fatal collison), perc_no_previous (percent of drivers with no previous fatal collisons), insurance_premiums, lossess (loss incured by insurance company).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>